Daniel Whatcott

Service Manager at BIOMEDICAL EQUIPMENT SERVICES CO

Boise, ID

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Daniel-Whatcott/8117bb889dee09d2

20 years of experience as a Certified Biomedical Equipment Technician (CBET) working for hospitals, healthcare companies, and original equipment manufacturers.

10 years of experience as a Clinical (Biomedical) Engineering Manager

5 years of experience as an Imaging Field Service Engineer

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Service Manager

BIOMEDICAL EQUIPMENT SERVICES CO - Meridian, ID October 2007 to Present

Install, repair, and perform pms on biomedical equipment at contracted facilities in Idaho and Wyoming. Document pms using our database, making a log of all repairs including software upgrades of equipment. Presented documentation and answered surveyor questions during recent DNV, and TJC surveys.

Conduct "in-service" training classes to teach medical staff the safe operation and proper use of equipment.

Hired additional technicians, managed company budgets for payroll, parts, education, and invoices. Set up a QA program to access customer satisfaction with company and seek ways to improve performance.

Diagnostic Ultrasound Field Service Engineer

PHILIPS MEDICAL - Portland, OR June 2004 to September 2007

- Performed pms and repairs of diagnostic ultrasound systems made by Philips, Siemens, and GE (multivendor) in assigned territory of Oregon and Washington.
- Documented repairs via Philips on-line database, and followed up with customer surveys.
- Traveled 90% of the time via company vehicle (road warrior).

Imaging Service Engineer

Providence Healthcare - Portland, OR June 2003 to June 2004

- Was part of an "in-house" group of technicians who serviced and maintained all the area Providence facilities imaging and radiology equipment.
- Performed pms of GE Lightspeed CT machines.
- Performed pms and repairs of diagnostic ultrasound machines made by Siemens and Philips.

Biomedical / Imaging Engineer

IASIS HEALTHCARE INC - Salt Lake City, UT December 2000 to November 2002

- Established and set up a new in-house biomedical service department for Rocky Mountain Medical Center then Jordan Valley Hospital to service the biomedical and imaging equipment at these and other IASIS facilities.
- ◆ Repaired broken or malfunctioning biomedical equipment, troubleshooting to component level.
- ♦ Set up new clinical equipment management software to integrate PMS and repairs to use bar-codes.
- ♦ Installed new Philips Dravidian monitors in ICU to expand the ICU monitoring capability by 30%.

Education

Certification in Anesthesia Machines

MindRay - Mahwah, NJ May 2021 to June 2021

Certificate in Computer Technology

Boise State University - Boise, ID January 2001

Associates of Applied Science in Electronics

Crowder College - Neosho, MO 1990

Skills

- BMET (10+ years)
- Field Service Engineer (7 years)
- Equipment Repair
- OEM
- Medical Imaging
- Service Technician Experience

Military Service

Branch: Air Force

Service Country: United States Rank: Civilian Contractor (Biomedical) February 2014 to February 2015

Contractor for Nellis AFB in Nevada, for biomedical equipment service.

Certifications and Licenses

CBET

March 2015 to Present

Certified Biomedical Equipment Technician by AAMI

Secret Clearance

Groups

Intermountain Clinical Instrumentation Society

April 2005 to Present

Board Memeber

Additional Information

SKILL SUMMARY:

- Experienced in passing several TJC, DNV, and CMS accreditation inspections.
- Perform field-service duties and sell additional medical equipment service contracts within the region.
- Manage other technicians on projects that were completed ahead of schedule and under budget.
- Trained and experienced using various types of computer hardware as well as several software programs including Windows, Excel, Word, and Access.
- Experienced in using various biomedical equipment database programs such as Four Rivers TMS, and DMLSS